Hello, everyone welcome to office and...it all together I'd like to
...and the session is also been streamed on channel nine so I'd like
...bank the audience watching online as well.
So, today I'm jason morse with me today is andru coats and work from the office
core experiences team office client effectively and we work
on building universal office apps out of our legacy cplus-plus code base.
So, at the end of the session will bring up the evaluation slide this is standard but please
evaluate the session we'd love to hear feedback and, we hope this session really is useful...
So, today main focus is
going to be on our approach to universal applicationshow office built the
...of universal applications we're going to talk about
a high-level approach some of our philosophy we're going to dive into details as well,
some of the stuff we do is a little esoteric
out we're going to try to have enough details especially in the realm
of integrating with cplus-plus integrating with your legacy code and,
integrated with some of your high-value content?
I will start off by talking about our values
our approach this is sort of the context or the lens
...which we view building these applications and the
...I'm going to talk about where the applications are today you know-how they're going what are approaches
are where you can get them various things like that.
So, to start off a throughout the conference and you know,
I've been sitting on...sessions as well there's been a lot of great stuff
about it's really easy to build applications it's really easy to do this you can do all this
stuff really quickly and that's great and that's actually really great for developers but
...the office perspective we don't care about easy or we do but it's not
our top priority,... for us quality
of experience for the user trumps everything and if it's more expensive were willing to make
pay that cost were willing to do that if it yields better experience.
So, to start with background...office and I know everyone has some opinions and
previous...office but there are many words people
used to describe office some of them positive some of them maybe not so positive
I see some smiles out there I'll pick up some I'll put
up some more positive words for it so that we don't have any suggestions but,
functional powerful you know, we're talking about office the desktop version
...thirty-two version classic office and this context
...it is big and complicated it can do a ton of stuff that has a ton
of our and we really believe in the value of that even today.
But, when you talk about mobile applications that may be is not which are looking for,
you know,
if any of you solve...theorems talk yesterday about them performance they
used analogy of building a car and when you build a mobile application you want to build a sports car you want to
build...high-performance fasten might car what office isn't really a
sports car maybe more like a bus...maybe not this bus you know,
it's more like an executive coach or is airforce one was a bus it would be that bus,
you know, it's got features it's got satellite hookup you can live your life
and that bus but it's not small and nimble?
And, we have gotten it to go pretty fast it considering how big it is
considering how much it does office actually really boots and,
moves along pretty quickly I did look for rocket
...slides but apparently that was not available on the internet shockingly.
So,...we talk about office and we talk about it in mobile context
people just don't think of it as fast and light and that's something we really need to change.
Looking at our code base our code base is...all
native code base now we have some manage application code for extensibility
but in the normal code flow is completely native and that is mostly cplus-plus.
It's thirty-years-old it started off
as predominately see and it's evolved over that time the new standards
and cplus-plus are actually really exciting to us people
...changing code over quickly the way we do things are changing and,
it's something that this code is old but it continues to
evolve and I'm sure for many of you who have large legacy code bases that's true
it's not completely static it has grown though it's gotten bigger and bigger and
right for...set up the stack I asked for a current count was
...hundred seventy one million lines of code that doesn't
include assets that doesn't include comments that doesn't include anything except for code?
And, that's a lot it's worth mentioning that word is not a fifty
five million line application this includes publisher includes project
includes outlook includes web apps includes a ton of stuff...really
and a broad...of applications and tools.
And, most other platform versions have been forks in the past so this
hundred-seventy one million lines does not include like the
...version does not include the ios version does not include diversions we've put
out on the other mobile platforms in the past we've.
Had successor releases on those platforms but we've done it by forking code.
This used to be okay
...over time the business has changed so when you look at the office business
we originally we sold office to machines and you would get your box of office and you would have your twenty-one
disks or whatever it was and you'd have to hours bonding time with your machine where you switch those
...around and maybe...a bunch of machines but that's not really the way
that things are done anymore now some of the single machine installs have gotten admittedly better since that
day but increasingly were selling to people.
And, this means a couple different things this has a some very important
ramming ramifications for us saatchi use the term portability of
experience in the keynote... it's a great phrase and it's one that really resonates with us as well the
experience of office if we're selling to you if you're buying office...sort of
a contract between us and you that we're going to try to get office wherever you are if you're using a
mobile device it should be on your mobile device if you're on a web page you should be able to access or documents on
a web page if you're on the rich client if you're on your laptop...you have a different way of accessing
...you have classic caps if...amac have ways of accessing wherever you are if
your customer office we should be able to reach you and those
...experiences should be consistent across those
platformsit should feel like office, you know,
and, it's a fine-line it should also feel like the application or platform
it's on but fundamentally people shouldn't have to figure out how to learn
...again it should be consistent experience and we roll-out
new features like we want to innovate we want to continue to innovate in the classic desktop we want
to innovate mobile but when we add those new features they need to be able to
be deployed to other platforms quickly we can't finish it on one platform
forking over have another team somewhere ago and modify it and
releases six months nine months a year later that just can't work anymore in the current business.
So, going back to the what do we care about if we don't care about easy for mobile
and in particular for these universal applications we care about
change in the adjectives we want people to think of it differently, you know,
we really want to build that sports par luxury sports
...or whatever we want fast and fun and it's not fun at least a pleasure to
use so, you know, creating your presentation or your document may not be fun but,
it can be a pleasure the apps themselves can feel-good can feel light can feel like they have
our but that our doesn't get your way.
We also care about sharing code.
We really need to make sure we're not doing this for...were not duplicating efforts because if we want to
role things out we have to have a shared code base we still need to
relieve room for differentiation on platforms you know,
people who are and platform expect certain things...platformyou've heard a lot
about the new features on the windows platform and there's some really cool stuff on that
and we need to leave room that we can extend the apps on those platforms take advantage of
those great platform specific features and we do care about development speed
it it's not quite true that we don't care about easy but we have a lot of developers and,
if we can build complex and somewhat dubious solutions
essentially and then roll them out to other people will do that if we can build something
...expensive once and,
it saves us time or has a better experience we'll make that tradeoff every single time?
looking at how we actually use the platform we started these applications in the eight-point
one timeframe and in that time frame this is
...threshold or...windows term sorry.
The central question was we're going to build demo applications and how do we use
those applications as fast as possible it's very hard to retrofit performance
if you're building app it's much easier to get everything right from the start so
the question became how do we use animal as fast as possible?
So, the first...we came to was traditional data mining was just way too slow ...hopefully you saw the
x...presentation if you...developer use exponent transition to
x find if...app code...structured in such a way that camp support
...changer app code so can use...if you still can't do that
use code behind it is a dramatic performance boost to...that...
And, you will talk about how we solve that we probably would have a solution based on
x...now if it had been available but,
we'll talk about what we did do don't make every property dependency property it's some of these
features are really nice but custom dependency properties are slowed you don't have that
...foundational piece of your app it'll slow things down and,
then this one seems obvious
but the truth is it's still an easy thing to make a mistake on be cautious with
a number of elements you create use the one things you need collapsed visual
trees still have cost dynamically create those especially if
there large you can do encode behind in windows ten you can use extra for
load strategy it's actually a really great solution for that if you're if you're supporting eigth-point-zero
eight-point one apps having large gsm trees has cost that's been
largely,
largely addressed in threshold but if you're on those older platforms
it's important to note that especially and elements or...content that is scaling
with user data and that sort of our own internal rule its content is
proportional to the to data coming in from the user if it's not bounded?
Really avoid data binding really
look at your templates look at everything make sure you have no extra elements
...the end of the day that's your cost that's your performance cost.
And, then don't be afraid of code behind many of these things it's nice to get something that works
entirely...markup but if you're trying to really optimized the experience
codebook behind is really a tool that gives you absolute control...absolute
our and many of the performance improvements campy obtained without code behind?
And, x find as an example essentially generating very particular,
particular code behind for-you and,
it makes a huge difference to so don't be afraid code behind particularly if you're on eight-point
our eight-point one-and-a-half to do downloadable support so to talk more about data
...have andrew come up
thank you thank you jason hello everyone so,
I want to talk a little bit about how we work with data
...says as...mentioned ...
heard by now data binding example is not the most performance way to get
data into them all and as you also mentioned back when we startedon windows eight-point
one x bind did not exist so we're looking
...building these universal office applications when...looking at how to get...into
the tamil really the only efficient way to do that with use code behind?
One of the great things about using code
by an essential using a cplus-plus eecs.
The code behind control directly to
a existing nativedata types so it's a map everything in math classes...
back table a generate create additional methods...take performance cost.
But, also if you have as much you...we do in office you end up
running a lot of code behind to get your data into...if you're not using data
...so, we wanted to look at a way...to help...developers right
...code behind because a lot of that could behind it ends up being fairly repetitive
it's basically the same code of...of again, yeah,
listening to the...notifications...doing switch statements
...call backs...called accent it's fairly...code tonight.
we came up with was a custom solution based on bunch custom mock-up
and as annual files that we call that example scripting.
And, basically what we do is we preprocess as...files doing bill.
So,...customer cup and as...files defines three basic things.
Defines a set of properties that we're going to expose from a control.
...it defines some scripts which are really small
segments of code behind...will actually do the work to push that data
into is elements...the...also defines when we want...scripts...
And, then from this mock-up we generate...of the code behind that...the sort of
...of code behind that you have to do by hand if you're...it.
And, this is very
...to what the valentin did with...we of showed them...solution and,
...feedback...an insights on on-base what we did to help them influence that design.
So, this is a quick glimpse of what some of
...looks like which really doesn't make a whole lot like newsml.
So, here where defining a property was saying this control
as a property of technical and that's a cool user.
And, this script basically says.
I take the name from the user I'm going to set into text of this text and that
will just become code behind the standard cx code in the code behind.
And, lasting it defines is a trigger says when we want that
scripts to one...usa...it's going to go when the name of that user changes.
So, affiliated if you look at this script is really doing is basically the same
...bind allows you to do.
It's a little less...looking but,
we were working outside of the platform sources this is what we came up with.
Swivel this out to the whole office old that was working on family life.
And, it really performed what...work quite well but the main
...of the...getting thing was to avoid using data binding and to get
...performance gains of not using data binding using code by instead.
And, this should be similar to what you see if you switzer text by and I think when we
...count the votes is one of the more example heavy you office applications
...have a lot of data binding research them from data mining to as I was getting solution
we made the...fifty-cent faster so it does make a big difference.
there were some other effects of this crazy scripting solution.
One thing is when the designing it we really wanted it to be a
...data mining especially for pushing data into is eml
butts we're allowing people to write ui...and that code in
...ui files so once we have that
...file it became convenient place for people to stop adding logic and
...overtime more and more code...added to
...files and that obviously becomes code that is
ui specific.
Platform specific is hard to unit test.
Which really brings us to know how should
...building ui and then the most fundamental thing is your business logic should be separate from
a ui it's really important have a good boundary here?
This is always...and we change I knew I
...frequently...business logic.
You really don't want to your business logic mix-up the why we are constantly
...ui trying out new designs.
in today's cost platform world it's even more important...business logic is not
...I want to be able to share...business logic across multiple platform.
...take a business logic you put...and it's nice...object.
But, then to really enable sharing of that business logic
...how you use that business logic.
You can have a ui talk to the business logic.
But, you really don't want the your business logic directly talking
to you I mean you can't replace you...different implementation
...it makes unit testing orimplementing a completely different ui on another you
I platform fateful...if you follow this allows you to...objects...business logic.
So, as I mentioned.
A lot of people salivating more code...we really wanted a now you I files and
part of this was because the mock-up generally a bunch useful code.
Hank develop...a fundamentally a little lazy.
So, if there's a choice to...it and you I files
...code for them all manually valuable...code that...generate code for them.
So, where we're moving to a world where we're actually going to use
markup for generating of you models as well...going to?
Define...model...what properties...events
...some of the model and then we can order generate that as well we can generate the top...
get sets the notify poppy changing...stuff this also allows us to order
generate ...top lead the imc implementation we also generate
...tuples with other...platforms so jj...interop
...ui and get to see...to ios...kind of thing through them and
...the jason's talk more about the cplus-plus innovation.
in office we ended up with large quantities of native models we wanted to interact with and we have native
...we had with all sorts of native code that really we needed to interact with from sample
and...transmit...animal and, there's a great mechanisms...for doing that
...cplus-plus eecs but it turns out when we rolled this out the office team
...the number one question for us was not how to use sandler how to do a lot of
eml things they found sample actually fairly easy to use but we
have a lot of questions about cplus-plus eecs so I want to cover sort of how we use
cplus-plus as glue between the applications so sequence posse
acts are...preferred...cx because it's less of a mouthful it really does making
...writing code against...dramatically faster all showboat that in a second.
More importantly or as importantly it also automate the process of
...md files when...
files are windows metadata files and they define what your objects can do when
you're when you're objects are being used by csharp this is necessary for reflection type operations
...compiler actually uses to generate type info for your objects as well.
See...it does have some drawbacks though cx can...complexity or cost the
it it's easy to write the code it's not always clear what it's going to be
doing and it does also have limits on how to integrate cplus-plus.
It ends up being a great tool for it but you really have to know how to use a correctly or
will be somewhat frustrating it's also not
cross platform when we ended up writing and setting things up in such a way that developers
...all their code in there in the code behind it all
...cplus...plus eecs code and that wasn't
process platform it was harder to unit test so it's another thing to be careful of if
you're writing large quantities of cplus-plus eecs code it is not portable but,
it does work great as a...interop layer it really allows you to not have marsh
ling cost and use correctly it's really great?
So, to understand this I'm going to do a sort of side-by-side so on the left I have cx
class this is
href class this corresponds to a windows runtime object on the right
as a cplus-plus representation of the class and this uses something called wr
...I'm not sure whether you're familiar with this or not the stands for windows runtime library and it's
in the sdk all of the things I mention here...the public sdk they are not
super documented but we're going through the same code baths that you can go through as well so
...class over here it has a public session section.
So, I have a property and a method in this section and,
what cplus-plus eecs is going to do is it's going to build and interface
...so if you look on the right-hand side that I through public non virtual xyz
a generated interface that contains those methods it turns the property into a
...and setter function and,
it translates them into...results because the actual interfaces are use
...results cx will wrap things and exceptions for you it makes it kind of nice easy-to-use
but the actual underlie intact is old-school com style interop?
If you inherit from
...interface it works in an exact same way it's just overrides all of
...stuff so far is in the actual published version of the object so it's accessible
avp from csharp...accepts accessible from outside your binary.
There's another kind of scoping
are called internal and csharp developers may be familiar with this may be new
to cplus-plus developers and internal actually corresponds
to the public section of the cplus-plus class but not the published
...section so this is not
available to csharp is not available outside the binary but if you
were inside the binary you can just call these as public functions so I have a native type
in here there's a little bit of a typo between the two but the point is you can have any kind of data typing
passed through...as members on these functions finally private works just like private.
when you're writing code inside cplus-plus...makes example easy here's...code take a control
...the render transforms x coordinate two-twenty five?
Pretty simple but.
It turns into the following code you have to query over from control ty element and you
call get render transform this gets...the
...transform actually sometimes create the object but they will cassette for you return the type back you'll
...address release...on that and you qi again to translate
transform and then finally even call put eczema translate transform
now that sounds like a lot it's actually not all that bad in
isolation the problem comes when you write the following code.
Now there's sort of a contracts and virtual interfaces and in
...interfaces where people can do crazy stuff like tear
offs like every time you call query interface you could return a different interface if you want no
one does but because you could the platform can't optimize these
lines so every one of these lines will actually repeat all of those lines above
and if you're using this for if in most cases this is not a problem but if you're using this
and high-frequency code list items are common case of high-frequency code so if you
write this code without thinking about it can actually become a performance a significant part of your
performance.
when using cplus-plus types and, as I said for us one of the big questions how to integrate
our legacy types in most cases you can use am pretty easily from once you
get the types they just you can use them like you can and cplus-plus
...the question is how to get those into the object in the first-place in the same
binary use that internal scoping...a...it's easy but, across
...it gets a little bit harder we've we had a couple different patterns we used for this
...patterns you can look up the
pattern so that you can actually reinterpret cast between object and I
and spectral star and do some fancy stuff there really the one we found that work the best it's a
...feels like a little bit of a hack but soviet was actually just
...methods you can...method that takes a href class
amac a model and because the function executes on the inside of the binary it can call
those internal function so some of our scripting stuff actually generates
setter functions that allow you to set things...binary into it?
one of the more frustrating to me at least limitations...eecs
is you can't inherit from native types so if you actually want to
expose your cplus-plus classes to x bind you need to find some way to
wrap them so, the most common way to do this is to put in a
...class around them using cx and,
then you embed the classroom side so I have a sample uniform simple class here has
a property change notification and gets a string so.
Rapping with cx is pretty straightforward if a bit wordy you take your base property notify
change or not...changed implementation and you basically forward things through
and, the should be relatively straightforward to everyone here.
If you actually want to use...cplus-plus inheritance if you want
...cplus-plus eecs it turns out you can do it it's a little bit tricky
and very non obvious and the way to do it is found in a way
that the platform sdk itself is generated if you look in the sdk you'll
see that there for windows dot you why...dot ideal there's an
...file there's about age file and...associated with
...the files and what happens is if you build-up an ideal file and,
I have some example code here you create a runtime class and some interfaces you can run
it through middle at with the...rt flag...will spit out a header and
when md file for you if they're can only really bone when I'm deeper binary if
it's a separate binary you can just use that if you want emerged...there's a tool called
md emerge from this may involve some custom-built steps it's a little tricky but
it is possible and then once you set this up you can use the wr
all which I mentioned before hand to actually implement this so
from this you can actually compose it with your native types you
can compose it with anything you can mix and classic com you can mix in other
I am spectacles it's really gives you the full our
of cplus-plus now you don't necessarily want to do this for everything but
it's something you can do if you really have performance intensive code and this avoids
having multiple objects...you can have a single object exposed?
Right so I'm going to switch gears and get back to them a little
so, in office we have we have a lot of existing resource pipelinesyou know,
we have a...tables...huge amounts of images
we've invested a lot of time and money in these in these resource pipelines
easy...pipelines what designed
...classic office they're...data office so these are these are not
zambia resources but we really want to continue to use them in...applications.
Example has a custom resource loader that allows you to basically a provide
interfaces...say when you need to loading resource tell me which resource some
slowed and I'll give it to allows you to integrate
...existing resources into is an...now they basically take the string invented
...example file and give you...
Which is great but most of our resource
pipelines the index space that's a little more efficient generate look things up
by index and then string maps so to avoid doing is extra-strength look up at
...we actually at again take up preprocessor to the
...and if we see some mock-up that
...innovating into a color resources we have some custom
...says hey if we have a blush that's called pain background
will compile-time the place that with custom resource brush one-two-three
and...runtime we see to do it and index look...and save the actual?
So, we, yeah, like we do this with a bunch of resources...strings colors combine...
You might be wondering why don't you just...email...sports
...nums integers you can type in the name of it that the nice
...fashion what great...
Well, we actually tried...icon control we have an icon control
...the icon id which is one of ims.
So, what happens when you...a typed example
xhtml really needs to understand a little more information about that type?
...generate some type information when you expose...to them so here's
...the generated type information looks like in cx phone...
If you look at the code that's...color here.
And, you imagine that maybe we...and we have many thousands of icons
in office this might not be the best
idea to do I don't think we made up of...hadley happy for a little while and we did this.
So, as I mentioned ...can make on control.
We did thismostly to abstract the implementation of
icon from a developers we did this because inverses of the
release work changing how we do icons on desktop we use p...
the for icons back in windows eight-point one windows
into...for...fonts which provide vase benefits of
...a pe files...particular you can support multiple different scales
...and stuff without having to ship a whole bunch of different versions of the same image and,...
nothing they did in windows ten as they move support of to
...control the snouts...code fonts...familiar with the
left control I know ...it's...it's...a sort of light-weight version
of text block doesn't support the same crazy set of text
...functions that text what does...just displaying
an icon you don't really need like font fullback logic and analyst other stuff that
textbook...for-you so-if icons you should look into using deliverance that so,
...changing this overtime like as you move
...created icon a creative fonts icons some icons
...some would be some of via fonts.
So, this control allows us to hide that from
a developers and it's a relatively a simple idea
...sort of simple flow here the logic of what we actually do an
...metadataworking out which I call we should be using when
is a fairly complex thing that we want to keep
...button for instance...not always be some
...six some other...some of the symbol but,
the icon control basically look up...metadata decides
...this one's this one's...image allocate...control satisfy content
on this icon this is a ...colored function self-critical...control...my content.
I've talked about data...resources.
What about those
document surfaces that very custom ui in office?
...these canvases highly sophisticated
dynamic animated interactive you name it this...has to do it.
So, back in office twenty thirteen.
On the classic...classic office applications.
...all of...doing to direct...which helps us migration.
We also when...content to.
...different two-d layers.
And, then we use these layers and in classic desktop...layers to compose the seem to
animators this different layers of anticipate best animation effects.
Now...a great story they have a bunch of different...elements...direct,
direct text interop directly...eml you can put these elements anyway
...you can compose them you can animate them togethergenerally it's a seamless
...direct text content.
A little bit about what code the architecture here looks like we have a
giant section of the shared layout code menu encode the use.
Of the core of applications.
And, that's...across platforms and we have an abstraction medical
space.
...handles the creation of these layers.
And, animation of those layers ...classic of office applications we
...own composite an...animation system to do this.
Example it's much simpler we just create example elements motels...the composition animation
And, then we have implementations...some of the other platforms with the greater or less
...successes as the platforms have better...all not as much because
Just talk a little bit about animations.
The ability to main ways to animations example.
The theme animations which are great the dead easy you
...apply...transition to an element to a panel...change the and
...animate want to be changed.
But, that fairly limited in customization you basically get
...transition does and if you don't want that then you will have to do...lawson which is
storyboards that.
Fully...can...all different kinds of animations is...sports.
But, there fairly the both to set up
...class...a lot...mock-up...code.
And, the difficult to make consistent classier ui we have a lot of you I
want animations be consistent closet and
...share storyboards across different pieces of...
They also require custom code to triggers animations.
So, I'm...quick show.
Solutions animations which is a control
...re...office panel.
And, to do that I'm going to show you autotest application that we have here which is
an application where we actually requirements of...developers when writing control.
Toattest page in this application...test that control in isolation manually
play with it ...we have some integration attest system to...testing its control...
So, in this page we have a little control panel the playing with
...panel which handles...animations for us.
So, I'm going to hit is I messiah changing layout of the objects in this panel.
You'll see the that the object animate...you positions.
Now I'm doing is just changing the layout this panel and everything's smoothie animated...new positions.
And, I can I can customize animations so I can I can slow them down a little
...dynamics one other thing on point out here.
Is the as I'm
...layout while they're still automating very smooth smoothly moving from
the current position while the animated to the new target that especially moving to?
And, I'll just show one-click other example...of this.
Who have a bunch because I'm going to add a whole pile more control
...panel now smoothie anyway and except this
...seems to be a little slower?
And, I can change the size of these guys and they
will also smoothly animate any size and use new position...same time.
So, this custom panel
niggers the flexibility storyboards we can use...the customizations even
do storyboards and also actually integrates the existing animations we have
...for desktop.
We shed definitions cost.
...to platforms so we can have...have a similar field...office experience.
And, we automatically trigger them on reposition...hide that's how it's implemented.
First thing we do is we add a couple properties to
...panel ones animation class defines.
Which...by animation definitions which we using...elements within this panel?
We also have an attached to the propertywhich is a great way is
...extend the platform?
We use that to specify individual elements within...panel that...maybe use a
different set animations that's why...element was going...had a different animation class adamant.
...center measurement ranges usual but then join
a range will dynamically create storyboards on-the-fly to animate what changed.
So, here's a little segment of what...range might look like.
The beginning...
Manger child...to...aboard.
And, we animatevendor transform.
Calculate where the element used to be animate
format position two-two-zero twenty it'll be it'll be showing
...final position...we just desktop that animation.
Salads...
what happens if the position changes...is...
Take a closer look at this ...old position that's where the
element was going to...if we use this code here well,
actually if the position change that we're going from a to be a
...say accuracy will immediately snappy to be if you this code here so
the solution is actually it's not...difficult but it's completely not obvious.
We actually always...earlier.
We do the entire layout using vendor transform only and then when
...creating a storyboards we only need to specify the final location weary specify
...going to and we can leave the farm expression off entirely on the
And,...in that case if they'll pick up the...value even if it's in the middle of
animation so...lattices smoothly change web animation ii.
The other thing up analyses is resize animations this is a question that I see come
...internally places and externally...come up all-time.
And, zone nearly support resize animations generally what people
those is they start out by to animate...property or height property
...sample kinda yell at you and...and...animation.
And, what that really means is that animation is going to running like that it's not going to run on
...composite so while animation may look
or some of them develop...box when you put that on some low
...low-end hardware like a low-end foam?
Also...application is doing something else in the life at suddenly that animation
will get jerky a analysis...looking.
...use the scale transform.
That will one of the composite will be nice and smooth.
But, if you've got like textile images in your content
...also stretch those...which is probably not what you really want.
Solutions is again relatively simple but we split up...into multiple as.
We continue to...the...of the panel using the transforms.
...we...a scale transform on a background and the
...elements so we can
...size the...looks like this so the sizing.
...continue to animate the contents to handle a new...smoothly...and,
everything looks great as...and again we...this and arrange that happens completely automatically.
So, I'm going to close out the presentation by talking about where we are today
we're currently getting ready to ship these applications
are not quite done yet but they include word excel powerpoint one note
and new mail-in calendar applications one...is of course been in the store for some time
and if...the new builds of windows ten you should be able to get them from the store so please download them
try them out submit feedback submit reviews
...love to get feedback on these things
it's worth noting that these are completely built on the public platform the way we use
them on those applications the things we do our all public we don't have any back doors
or inside type of negotiations with salmon
it's all public so it's all possible for-you to do whether it's advisable
a or little crazy is another question but.
And, the windows ten improvements are big deal to us you heard a lot of great things this
during this conference about new performance improvements and those will help us as well we're very excited
about them are working to integrate them as fast as we can so, over the next couple months
we expect the office applications will get even better as well.
...we invented...data binding replacement but I'm going to promote x
...one more time if it...existed then we would...used it we
...we're generating models now we would have generated interop
...fry and spectacle rather than generating
complex templates that do sort of compile-time type systems.
It's also they're also truly universal apps and this was
a philosophy we had or sort-of...approach we had
...from the get-go we knew we wanted to do this we knew we wanted to be dynamic we
...one package for mobile and for
desktop we wanted to adapt to changes on-the-fly you know, it's important
us that we can ...note have to you don't have to reboot the application you know, the I...
you guys saw a or hopefully saw the continuum for phones and that's something that's really exciting for us so
applications will be able to shift from a phone centric
...to a truly desktop centric qi dynamically.
As a philosophical
...we wanted to use consistent crossover points this is similar to all of our
...animal we have a philosophy that developer should never hard code anything
whatever because it makes it very hard to change it when you inevitably need
...so it's really important that you don't have one app
changing six eighty and one app changing at seven hundred and getting...so,
you establish your points assume you're going to change things assume you're going to
changer colors assume you're going to change everything and set...to make it easy to do and,
then in terms of building you why we had a lot of sort of layering principles
...pictures I pulled up here are the same build same version of the application
this is word and, you see the right-hand side is what we call the
...ui which is the phone version of the ribbon it comes up from the bottom
on the left is the standard ribbon you would see on desktop of universal ...
those are the same controls and...and those controls inside don't really know
whether living they don't care they just those controls know-how to how to render you know,
keeping these principles of you have elements that are loaded
from data the way you do that is relatively the same but you can change the layout middle so,
effectively abstracted effectively and,
make sure that you can dynamically swap those layouts.
And, lastlycode sharing...is a big one for us and universal
as built out of our main tree it's not based on a fork this is the first-time we really were
doing a mobile release out of this code tree it's the same tree that produces
when thirty-two same...produces the web applications and,
actually if you guys followed android the android tablet version
that was released recently is out of the same tree as well and,
the universal applications are sort of a new shared code base for
officer for at least mobile office and android is built out of that same code base so when we look at
the code sharing...this these stats...here are from
a powerpoint but when we look at code sharing between them
were at about ninety six percent shared and universal and, that includes...when you excludes
animal we're at about ninety eight-point six submit a little bit there are platform light up
some things like thatwhen you look
android it's ninety five percent shared with ninety nine point seven so almost
hundred-percent code sharing between android and universal when you exclude
...the job...
So, this is something we're really thrilled about and something that we want to
extend and continued to grow and develop and bring the other applications
...versions we've done into the fold.
So,...that I'm going to refer you to
a couple sessions that were done earlier more work closing out the show here but,
the data binding talk and this...performance talk really have a lot of great information and them
if you didn't attend those go watch them I also referenced here a presentation.
My boss actually gave had the at scale conference and,
it's worth looking at its the office approach to cross platform you...and,
cplus-plus app building and it's actually...focused more just
cross platform coding so it's worth...look as well and, with that evaluate the session and we're going to use the
rest the time for any questions you have we don't we don't have I don't think the
when site windows insider lounges going to be available because the build this
...but, we'll be here as long as
have questions so if you have questions for us just come up to the microphones and thank you.
Just a question you see the cplus-plus layer as a net positive or negative...if
...from scratch today would you still have a cplus-plus layer.
As a common layer console your platforms I think we would it, you know.
There is no perfect or one-size-fits-all solution when you look at the size of
office it's impossible to get the amount of things we do into?
fitting a huge amount of features and functionality encode into a very narrow surface you know,
it I talked about the fast bus and desktop considering it's,
you know, millions and millions of lines of code it
actually runs really fast and it's really the our of native code that allows that to happen and,
a lot of the manner solutions are really great but we're sharing
that code base with the desktop client and cplus-plus is one of the few languages
lets us do that and, I also think it's worth mentioning that if
...me five years ago how excited I was about cplus-plus you know, it be like well, you know,
it's really fast but,
it's actually evolved a lot as a language the cplus-plus eleven ...
the extensions that have been done or not extensions but support for that
in visual studio are great and something that we've really
...and people...excited about embracing so I think it's a one you absolutely
need to use has little our get as much performance users little battery
as possible it's toss the best solution and it works, you know, you can have a
core that works across android ios when thirty-two?
Whatever platform you might be on and, you know,
we want to have that core we...unit test that...and,
then we want to...sort of front-ends that work different ways.
I was able to make to do data binding one-button
act spine that you mentioned is that something is available to wpf words just for universal
I think it is just for universal
...is something that is I think just those...code base so?
Ok, well.
Thank you all and we will be around here if you have any...thanks.